Syahril Ashraf, Laravel Developer

Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia - 60135077314 - syahrilashraf769@gmail.com



LINKS <u>Github</u>, <u>LinkedIn</u>, <u>Portfolio</u>

PROFILE

Full-Stack Developer with over a year of experience in web development. Skilled in Laravel, JavaScript, PHP, and Git. Capable of working on projects from start to finish, meeting deadlines, and improving processes. Able to work well with team members and stakeholders

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Jul 2023 — Present

Full-Stack Developer - OnPay Solutions Sdn Bhd, Kuala Lumpur

- Successfully developed advanced modules that significantly increased user subscriptions and revenue.
- Implemented system updates and alterations based on comprehensive design specifications, ensuring seamless functionality and alignment with business requirements.
- Developed and integrated advanced modules with multiple payment gateways, including ToyyibPay, CHIP, senangPay, and Billplz, enhancing the platform's payment processing capabilities and user experience.
- Collaborated closely with the technical and marketing teams to effectively communicate
 the features and benefits of the newly developed advanced modules. Provided detailed
 explanations and demonstrations to enable the marketing team to effectively pitch the
 modules to clients and devise targeted marketing strategies.

Aug 2023 — Dec 2023

Full-Stack Developer (Part-time) - Jr Techs Solutions, Kedah

Government Project:

- Implemented effective project management methodologies such as Agile to ensure efficient resource allocation, risk mitigation, and timely project completion. Regularly provided progress updates and status reports to keep stakeholders informed and aligned.
- Successfully managed and delivered government projects, ensuring compliance with all regulatory requirements and achieving project goals within budget and on time.

NGO Project:

- Developed and implemented a comprehensive membership management system for an NGO that previously relied on manual record-keeping for tracking membership fees.
 The system streamlined the organization's financial processes, eliminating errors, inconsistencies, and potential financial leakages.
- Integrated an online payment gateway into the membership management system, enabling members to conveniently pay their fees online. This implementation significantly improved the efficiency and accessibility of the payment process, resulting in a 90% reduction in membership payment issues.
- Conducted training sessions and provided ongoing support to ensure smooth adoption of the new system.

Feb 2023 — Jun 2023

Full-Stack Developer (Intern) - Bayam (M) Sdn Bhd, Cyberjaya

- Integral part of the team that developed and maintained the back-end functionality of the client's system.
- Streamlined data retrieval processes, resulting in a 20% increase in back-end efficiency.
- Collaborated on API design and development, providing robust data solutions to meet business needs.
- Gained hands-on experience in working within an Agile development.

Mar 2021 — Jul 2022

Full-Stack Developer (Freelancer) - Masjid Al Wustha, Kedah

- Developed E-Khairat Management System to help in increasing productivity by 50%.
- Achieved seamless integration of E-Khairat with the ToyyibPay payment gateway and an SMS gateway API for reminders.
- Optimized the website's load performance, enhancing speed by 50%.
- Conducted client training sessions to discuss system flow and demonstrations.

Mar 2021 — Jul 2021

WordPress Developer (Freelancer) - Yayasan Islam Negeri Kedah, Kedah

- Developed and maintained a charity website, updating plugins and functionalities as required.
- Actively engaged with the client in website development planning and design.
- Facilitated online training about the content management system for staff.
- Optimized WordPress sites for performance, reducing page load times by 20%
- Designed and developed a website using WordPress that increased user engagement by 50%.

Oct 2019 — Jun 2020

Mobile App Developer (Freelancer) - SMK Agama Yan, Kedah

- Developed an Augmented Reality (AR) E-Learning application for SMKAY students.
- Collaborated with the Science teacher to create an interactive learning environment for third-grade classes.
- Won a gold award in July 2021, November 2020 and August 2020 in the competition.

Dec 2018 — May 2019

Mobile App Developer (Intern) - Mecacom Technologies Sdn Bhd, Kedah

- Designed and developed an Android application called Meca Desk, which streamlined task assignment from staff to technicians.
- Developed a REST API and deployed the application as an APK.

EDUCATION

Feb 2020 — Jun 2023

Bachelor of Information Technology (Hons.) in Software Engineering Universiti Kuala Lumpur Malaysia Institute of Information Technology

Jun 2016 — Feb 2019

Diploma of Information Technology Politeknik Sultan Abdul Halim Mu'adzam Shah, Kedah

SKILLS

- Laravel
- AlpineJS
- PHP
- JavaScript
- Git

REFERENCES

Mohd Dhiyaulhaq bin Mohd Ja'far, OnPay Solutions Sdn Bhd 60179115283

Muhammad Arfan Muhaimin bin Mohamed Shamsudin, Bayam (M) Sdn Bhd 601133900016

LANGUAGES

- Malay
- English